# Akash Rajak

LinkedIn | GitHub | Leetcode | HackerRank

Location: Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India Email: aakashrajak02@gmail.com | Mobile: +91 8980153352

## ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am a highly skilled Backend Developer with over 1 year of experience in Java, Python, SQL, HTML and CSS. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as Spring, Flask, Django, Angular and Azure and experience with objects and APIs.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

: Java, Python, JavaScript, C#, HTML, CSS, C++ Languages

Frameworks : Spring, Flask, Django, Angular, Azure

**Databases** : MySQl, SQLite

**Dev Tools** : Visual Studio Code, Git, Github, Intellij, Pycharm, Android Studio

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Associate Software Engineer**

Feb 2023 - Present

MAQ Software

Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India

- Designed and published a Pypi Package for Power Bi Documentation using Python, PowerBi, and OpenAI.
- · Worked with OpenAl APIs to retrieve and display the metadata information of the Power Bi Reports.
- Working on Automation Migration Tool between the Qlik and Power Bi Reports.

**Q&A Expert** Sep 2022 - Jan 2023

Chegg India

Remote - Vadodara, Gujarat, India

- Worked as **Problem Solver** in Computer Science domain on Chegg Expert site.
- Solved the Q&A problems in Python, Java, C, C++, SQL, C# Languages.

#### **Software Developer Intern**

Jul 2021 - Aug 2021

Exposys Data Labs

Remote - Vadodara, Gujarat, India

 Worked on updating the Cryptography RSA algorithm to secure chat messages with 95% high accuracy on security and with efficient time.

## **EDUCATION**

## Indian Institute of Information Technology, Kalyani

Kalyani, West Bengal, India May 2019 - May 2023

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science & Engineering CGPA till Sem - 7: 8.81

#### **PROJECTS**

Project 1 React.js, Redux, PHP, MySQL Git Source Code

- Designed and developed a clean and modern website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Optimized website for speed and user experience
- Utilized responsive design to ensure compatibility across all devices
- Deployed on GitHub pages via GitHub Actions

**Project 2** Node.js, Express, JavaScript, Git Source Code

- A CRUD application exposed using a RESTful API made with Node.js
- Exposed POST, GET, PATCH and DELETE HTTP methods using Express

## CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified Web Developer by the W3C
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate
- · AWS Certified Developer Associate